<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Referential Labs, LLC</title>
    <link>https://referentiallabs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Referential Labs, LLC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://referentiallabs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://referentiallabs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://referentiallabs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About   Referential Labs grows, educates and assists software engineering teams.
 We are doing this by:
  helping executive teams identify the roles you need to hire given your strategic goals and find outstanding candidates to fill them
  providing world-class training and educational material on cloud delivery, distributed systems, and exploiting the benefits of functional programming no matter where you are on the adoption curve</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://referentiallabs.com/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://referentiallabs.com/training/</guid>
      <description>Training   We develop custom curriculum for teams and organizations based on your current technical stack as well as periodically offer open workshops virtually for individuals on more general topics related to functional programming, distributed systems, delivery pipelines.
 We utilize more hands-on interactive experience (in-person as pandemic allows, online exercises, and live sessions) where each student has their own cohort to share their learning journey.
Courses delivered to teams    Build Data Pipelines with Haskell   Leveraging abstractions like Functor, Foldable, Traverse, Free for profit, extensibility and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
